Inventory of the John C. R. Whiteley Papers, 1921 - 1947
John C. R. Whiteley Papers, 1921 - 1947
Special Collections & Archives, Wesleyan University
Whiteley, John Cecil Rushworth.
2003-83
1.75
4
John Cecil Rushworth Whiteley (1904-1959) was a member of the Wesleyan Class of 1925. He was also the recipient of a Rhodes Scholarship and attended Waldham College in Oxford.
The collection consists of Wesleyan University course-related papers, notebooks, and theses, along with notes and notebooks related to his studies at Wadham College. There is a scrapbook of letters, clippings, and invitations documenting his Rhodes Scholarship. One of the items of interest is an invitation to a dance given by the Prince of Wales and Lady Astor for all the Rhodes scholars. A list of Rhodes Scholars for that year also appears in the scrapbook.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisitions Information
Acquired in late 2003 as part of a bequest from the estate of Sarah M. Whiteley.
Biographical Note
John Cecil Rushworth Whiteley (1904-1959) was a member of the Wesleyan Class of 1925. Whiteley received a Rhodes Scholarship and studied at Wadham College, Oxford, from 1925 to 1928. He received a BA from the University of Oxford in 1927, and an MA in 1931. Whiteley worked at a number of paper companies as a financial officer. He married Dorothy Cooper in 1935.
Collection Overview
The collection consists of Wesleyan University course-related papers, notebooks, and theses, along with notes and notebooks related to his studies at Wadham College. There is a scrapbook of letters, clippings, and invitations documenting his Rhodes Scholarship. One of the items of interest is an invitation to a dance given by the Prince of Wales and Lady Astor for all the Rhodes scholars. A list of Rhodes Scholars for that year also appears in the scrapbook.
Online Catalog Headings
These and related materials may be found under the following headings in online catalogs.
Whiteley, John Cecil Rushworth.; Wesleyan University (Middletown, Conn.)--Alumni.; Rhodes scholarships.; Wadham College.
Detailed Description of the Collection
  - The Record, 1921 (West Philadelphia High School for Boys classbook) (Box 1)
  - Bennett's Lecture Notes, Wesleyan University
  - The Mathematical Theory of Investment, notes, Wesleyan University
  - Henry Merritt Wriston's Lectures on the Monroe Doctrine, Wesleyan University
  - Economics III, notes, Wesleyan University, pt.1
  - Economics III, notes, Wesleyan University, pt. 2
  - Junior Honors in History thesis, The International Relations of Canada and the United States, 1865-1871, 1924
  - Senior History Thesis, The Policy of the United States in Recognizing Governments in Centro-Latin America, 1925
  - History of the Class of 1925, Wesleyan University
  - 11 notebooks of notes from studies at Wadham College, Oxford (Box 2)
  - Excerpta E Statutis, Universitatis Oxoniensis
  - 2 legal-size notebooks of notes from studies at Wadham College (Box 3)
  - Scrapbook of letters, clippings, and memorabilia documenting Rhodes Scholarship
  - 2 notebooks, belonging to A.J. Firth, Merton College, Oxford, of notes on International Law
  - Offprint, America is a European Power, by Thomas B. McCabe, 1947 (Box 4)
  - Map of Paris
  - Passports
  - Photograph, [Psi Upsilon?, undated]